Every body needs a hero.
Osmosis Jones is a adventure, animation, action film directed by Bobby Farrelly.
A white blood cell policeman, with the help of a cold pill, must stop a
deadly virus from destroying the human they live in, Frank.
Osmosis Jones (voice), played by Chris Rock.
Thrax (voice), played by Laurence Fishburne.
Drix (voice), played by David Hyde Pierce.
Leah (voice), played by Brandy Norwood.
Shane Detorre, played by Elena Franklin.
Frank Detorre, played by Bill Murray.
Osmosis Jones is a 2001 American live-action/animated buddy cop action comedy
film directed by the Farrelly brothers and written by Marc Hyman.
The film stars the voices of Chris Rock, Laurence Fishburne, David Hyde Pierce, Brandy Norwood and
William Shatner, alongside Molly Shannon, Chris Elliott and Bill Murray in live-action roles.
It combines live-action sequences directed by the Farrelly Brothers
and animated ones directed by Piet Kroon and Tom Sito.
It follows the titular protagonist, an anthropomorphic white blood cell police officer, as he teams up with a
cold pill to protect his unhealthy human host from a deadly virus he unintentionally contracted.
The film premiered on August 7, 2001, and was
released theatrically three days later.
It received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the worldbuilding, animation, story and voice performances,
but criticized the inconsistent tone of the live-action portions and overusag of gross-out humor.
The film was also a commercial failure, grossing $14
million worldwide against a $70 million budget.
Despite the poor financial response, the film garnered success on home video and was followed by an animated television
series Ozzy & Drix, which aired on Kids' WB for two seasons and twenty-six episodes from 2002 to 2004.
The film explores themes of cold, flu, lethal virus, construction worker.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.